<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bastian Gruber</title>
    <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bastian Gruber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 08:56:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gruberbastian.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consuming, learning and operating on first principles</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/first_principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 08:56:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/first_principles/</guid>
      <description>After wanting to put words on my tinkering and thinking for probably the past 15 years, I came across a few articles which exactly do this. The first one was &amp;ldquo;How Julia Child Used First Principles Thinkinh&amp;rdquo; on Farnman Street. After reading it I realized that espeically in the last few years, I want to go to the basic ingredients of a certain genre or field instead of consuming what&amp;rsquo;s offered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working 100% remote in a distributed team</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/remote/</guid>
      <description>Info: This article was written in December 2019, before the pandemic hit the world.
My personal biggest factor being a software developer is to be able to work at the cutting edge of technology + industries and generally think about how life should look like in 10 or 20 years from now.
One of the biggest aspects, at least in my opinion, will be how we see companies, jobs and our current system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fond memories about co.up and MeetUp.com</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/coup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/coup/</guid>
      <description>I moved to Berlin in 2013, joining a StartUp called Dalia Reserach. Back then I still studied, and planned to finish my Bachelors at the beginning of 2014. But, the company needed people now so I quit my scholarship at Allianz, moved part-time to Berlin and commuted back and forth. I finished my studies in February and moved permanently to Berlin in March.
It was still late in the hype-cycle of the city, but you could feel the freedom to do whatever and whenever you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust for the Brave and True</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_brave/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 09:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_brave/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I wanted to make the switch from Frontend to Backend. One day I fell down the YouTube rabbit hole and (partly) watched a few tech talks. I realised that many of the really good talks were held at Clojure conferences. I looked into it, and decided to learn Clojure.
The lust for learning a new programming language often times comes from the sheer boredom of your old work, so you also want to redo part of yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explained: Futures in Rust for Web Development</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 20:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_futures/</guid>
      <description>As I explained in one of my last articles, Futures are one part of an asynchrounous environment. We need Syntax, Type and a Runtime to be able to run code in an non blocking way. Futures are the type part of the Rust async story.
 Content  The two perspectives What actually is a Future? When to use Futures? Why does using Futures save time? How to use Futures?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development with Rust - 03/x: Create a REST API</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 09:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_api/</guid>
      <description>Content  HTTP Requests POST/PUT/PATCH/DELETE are special The Job of a Framework Creating an API spec Crafting the API Input Validation Summary   APIs are the bread and butter of how a modern and fast-paced web environment. Frontend application, other web services and IoT devices need to be able to talk to your service. API endpoints are like doors to which you decide what comes in and in which format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explained: How does async work in Rust?</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_async/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/rust_async/</guid>
      <description>This article will outline an overview of the why and how async exists in Rust. The differences between concurrency, parallelism and asynchronous code won&amp;rsquo;t be covered.
Async Concept Asynchronous programming is a concept which allows not blocking the program workflow when waiting for the results of certain actions. So you can open a large file or query a database, but your program will continue processing each line afterwards.
This concept was first needed on the kernel level, because you want to be able to listen to music while you type something on your keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development with Rust— 02/x: Deploy your first App</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/deploy_rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 20:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/deploy_rust/</guid>
      <description>You can find the Introduction to web programming in Rust over here
  Update 08.07.2019: tide 0.2.0
This series has 3 goals  Show the obstacles new developers will face when programming in Rust but also its advantages when it comes to the specific topic (this time: Deployments). Show different options for web development in Rust. Always have an updated application in production afterwards.  Number three is super important for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Rust for NodeJS Developers</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/intro_rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 20:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/intro_rust/</guid>
      <description>You can find the second article in this series (&amp;ldquo;deploy your first Rust app&amp;rdquo;) over here.
 Rust is different. You can pick up Python or Ruby over the weekend, create a first CRUD application and be happy with the results.
With Rust… with Rust you will struggle to pass a String to a different method, change and return it. You then will order the Rust book, see its size, sigh and get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The easiest part of programming: Naming things</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/naming-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 09:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/naming-things/</guid>
      <description>Each system has its own believes and &amp;ldquo;common truths&amp;rdquo;. With system, I mean areas or professions. Education, Science, cooking etc. Each place where people come together and build a closed system where they operate in. From within, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to change a system, it&amp;rsquo;s just possible from the outside and by letting the old system die and create parallel to that a new one.
Programming is a system for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: One month of focus [UPDATE]</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/project-one-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/project-one-month/</guid>
      <description>Update: Since I wrote this blog post, created the second MeetUp for &amp;ldquo;Rust and Tell&amp;rdquo;, something unexpected happened: My daugther was born. Way too early (3 months), so instead of spending September in front of Rust code, I spend around 10 hours a day in the hospital. This being said: The project for October is: Don&amp;rsquo;t have any plans ;)
The dilemma of our privilidged and comfortable lifes as software engineers is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/talks/</guid>
      <description>From NodeJS to Rust [2020] I talked at the &amp;ldquo;Rust &amp;amp; Tell&amp;rdquo; MeetUp which I founded and co-host. The talk is and was about the journey of being a NodeJS developer becoming a fulltime Rust developer.
 Ego vs. Product development [2018] My talk was about the most common problem in any social environment: Your own ego. How showed the participants why the ego is there, and which mental models and techniques to use to overcome it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening the machines</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/openmachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/openmachine/</guid>
      <description>I am taking a break from the working world at the moment, and just finished travelling through North America for the last 3 months. Being back at my partner&amp;rsquo;s parents&#39; home in Canada, I browsed through the typical tech news at the end of a year. New iPhones here, better Google Pixels there. But, I am trying to apply a new rule for myself: Only buy something new if you have needed it every day for the past 30 days (with some minor exceptions of course).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git proficiency with rebase</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/gitprof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 18:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/gitprof/</guid>
      <description>I am a developer now for more than 10 years. Except a few years with SVN, I was solely working with Git. The best quote I got from one of my CTOs in the early days, was:
&amp;ldquo;Git is like the whole world, but we need just the size of a lake of it.&amp;rdquo;
You mainly use:
 git clone git pull git push git add git commit git checkout and git checkout -b  That&amp;rsquo;s mostly it, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching back to Sublime Text</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 10:40:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/switch/</guid>
      <description>Since the beginning of JavaScript on the desktop, aka Electron, I was happily switching to GitHubs Atom text editor. The benefits are obvious:
 Open Source Written in JavaScript, my main langauge Comes from a cool brand Faster development cycles  Ever since I switched, I loved Atom. Many plugins are enhancing your life as a developer. A few glitches here and there didn&amp;rsquo;t let me question my decision a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get started with BeagleBone</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/go-beaglebone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 10:20:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/go-beaglebone/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit, the power of IoT did not yet reach my little nerd life here in Berlin. Therefore, I took an effort this year and went to an IoT Hackathon. It was a fun weekend, I think there were just 5 developers and the rest of the crowd came from a social and educational background. Which made it even more fun and interesting.
Anyway, since this weekend I ordered a RaspberryPi and tried to do something useful with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downsizing and its side effects</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/sideeffects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 09:51:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/sideeffects/</guid>
      <description>For quite a long time now, I have been reading these two books:
 Early Retirement Extreme Your Money or Your Life  These titles suggest that it&amp;rsquo;s all about earning lots of money and then coasting your way through life. After reading the first few pages however, it becomes clear that the goal of these books is to provide you with a new mindset.
You can see all the hipsters in big cities are trying to do the same: eat locally, cook your own food, be aware of the consequences of your actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The beauty of DevOps</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 20:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/devops/</guid>
      <description>For my latest client, I got hired as a Fullstack JavaScript developer, plus DevOps, plus Frontend. The project is to rebuild the old PHP codebase onto a new stack containing Node, Angular and Microservices. The deployment is done via Docker and DockerCloud, hosted partly on AWS servers. As complicated as it sounds, new projects don&amp;rsquo;t have the nitty gritty problems legacy systems have. I think what you have to bring to such a project is a broad understanding of each technology and how they interact together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usedum in fall</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/usedum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/usedum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:37:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s me, Bastian, a passionate software developer. I am mainly working with Rust to create services for the web. Next to that I am writing for several tech magazines and publish articles on my own. Every now and then I get interviewedas well.
My Open Source contributions can be found mostly at GitHub, whereas my own projects are hosted at sourcehut. A detailed CV with projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on is on my LinkedIn profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 14:37:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gruberbastian.com/posts/interviews/</guid>
      <description>How and why to be a freelancer [german - 2019] An interviewwith my friends at Uplink, a german-wide freelancer community. This interview is in text form.
 Why learn Rust or any new programming language [english - 2019] I had an interview with Coder Society about the state of Rust and why it will play an important part in many companies toolchain in the future.
 Quo Vadis iOS [german - 2013] A second interview for Mac-TV.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
